<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Financial Statistics | Academic</title>
    <link>Jingwen99.github.io/tags/financial-statistics/</link>
      <atom:link href="Jingwen99.github.io/tags/financial-statistics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Financial Statistics</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/Jingwen99.github.io/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Financial Statistics</title>
      <link>Jingwen99.github.io/tags/financial-statistics/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transmission Mechanism of Geopolitical Risks on the Energy Market.</title>
      <link>Jingwen99.github.io/project/geo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>Jingwen99.github.io/project/geo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Reviewed 80+ research papers and reports, gaining valuable insights into the crude oil market&#39;s geopolitical risk perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developed a pioneering two-stage approach, integrating statistics, econometrics, macroeconomics, and behavioral finance theories, to analyze geopolitical risk transmission to the crude oil market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Utilized the time-varying parametric vector autoregressive (TVPVAR) model to demonstrate how geopolitical risk influences oil prices through various transmission paths, including micro and macro media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Identified two distinct geopolitical transmission paths-speculative behavior and economic activity&amp;ndash;to enhance energy-related decision-making.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Authored the paper &amp;ldquo;Transmission Mechanisms of Geopolitical Risks to the Crude Oil Market-a pioneering two-stage geopolitical risk analysis approach,&amp;rdquo; as the first author.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geopolitical Risks Diffusion in Energy Market:A Neural Network Perspective.</title>
      <link>Jingwen99.github.io/project/ml/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>Jingwen99.github.io/project/ml/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Analyzed 20+ papers on financial systems from a complex network perspective, focusing on stability, risk contagion, and immunization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attempted to employ Graph Attention Network (GAT) to predict oil price, incorporating geopolitical factors for unique insights into the energy market dynamics.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
